National Association of Corporation Schools Minutes and Publications 5452
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Association of Corporation Schools Minutes and Publications
1915-1921
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Association of Corporation Schools
5452
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Minutes (administrative records), records (documents), pamphlets.
Minutes and pamphlets of the National Association of Corporation Schools.
5623343
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, December 03, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1913, the National Association of Corporation Schools was a corporate training and consulting group that provided a variety of educational and management development services to businesses, government agencies and individuals. In 1923 it became the American Management Association.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of minutes and pamphlets of the National Association of Corporation Schools.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
National Association of Corporation Schools (U.S.)
5623343
- Founded in 1913, the National Association of Corporation Schools was a corporate training and consulting group that provided a variety of educational and management development services to businesses, government agencies and individuals. In 1923 it becam (Box 1)
  - Bulletin, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Item 1: Bulletin, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      By F. C. Henderschott. v.7:no.3 (1920:March). Item is in English.
  - 4th Annual Convention, 1916; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Item 1: Report of the Committee on Employment Plans to the Fourth Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
      By Committee on Employment Plans. May 30 - June 2, 1916. Pittsburgh, PA. Item is in English.
    - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Unskilled Labor to the Fourth Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
      By Committee on Unskilled Labor. May 30 - June 2, 1916. Pittsburgh, PA. Item is in English.
  - 5th Annual Convention, 1917; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Item 1: Report of the Executive Committee to the Fifth Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
      By Executive Committee. June 5-8, 1917. Buffalo, NY. Item is in English.
    - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Safety and Health to the Fifth Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
      By Committee on Safety and Health. June 5-8, 1917. Buffalo, NY. Item is in English.
    - Item 3: Report of the Committee on Trade Apprenticeship Schools to the Fifth Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
      By Committee on Trade Apprenticeship Schools. June 5-8, 1917. Buffalo, NY. Item is in English.
  - 6th Annual Convention, 1918; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Item 1: Report of the Committee on Unskilled and Semi-Skilled Labor nnual Report, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
      By Committee on Unskilled and Semi-Skilled Labor. Item is in English.
  - 7th Annual Convention, 1919; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Item 1: Report of the Committee on Employment to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
      By Committee on Employment. June 3-6, 1919. Chicago, IL. Item is in English.
    - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Executive Training to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
      By Committee on Executive Training. June 3-6, 1919. Chicago, IL. Item is in English.
    - Item 3: Report of the Committee on Methods of Instuction to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
      By Committee on Methods of Instuction. June 3-6, 1919. Chicago, IL. Item is in English.
    - Item 4: Report of the Committee on Trade Apprenticeship to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
      By Committee on Trade Apprenticeship. June 3-6, 1919. Chicago, IL. Item is in English.
    - Item 5: Report of the Committee on Unskilled Labor and Americanization to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
      By Committee on Unskilled Labor and Americanization. June 3-6, 1919. Chicago, IL. Item is in English.
  - 8th Annual Convention, 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Item 1: Report of the Committee on Job Analysis to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
      By Committee on Job Analysis. May 31- June 4, 1920. New York, NY. Item is in English.
    - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Profit Sharing and Allied Thrift Plans to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
      By Committee on Profit Sharing and Allied Thrift Plans. May 31- June 4, 1920. New York, NY. Item is in English.
    - Item 3: Report of the Committee on Unskilled Labor and Americanization to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
      By Committee on Unskilled Labor and Americanization. May 31- June 4, 1920. New York, NY. Item is in English.
  - 9th Annual Convention, 1921; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Item 1: Report of the Committee on Employment to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
      By Committee on Employment. June 7-10, 1921. Niagara Falls, NY. Item is in English.
    - Item 2: Report of the Committee on Job Analysis to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
      By Committee on Job Analysis. June 7-10, 1921. Niagara Falls, NY. Item is in English.
    - Item 3: Report of the Committee on Visualized Training to the Seventh Annual Convention, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
      By Committee on Visualized Training. June 7-10, 1921. Niagara Falls, NY. Item is in English.
  - Special Report Service, 1918; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Item 1: Office Work Schools, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
      By Executive Secretary's Office. Special Report Service, report no.2. Item is in English.
    - Item 2: Methods of Industrial Work, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
      By Executive Secretary's Office. Special Report Service, report no.3. Item is in English.
  - Confidential Report Series, 1919; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Item 1: A Preliminary Survey of the Problem of Representation in Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
      By Office of the Managing Director. Confidential Report Series, report no.4. Item is in English.
  - National Association of Corporation Schools, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Item 1: National Association of Corporation Schools, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
      By National Association of Corporation Schools. List of Company Members (Class A), Officers, and rules. Item is in English.